const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following can cause inhibition of action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Influx of chloride","bool":true},{"option":"Influx of potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of bicarbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries gives rise to the nutrient artery of the fibula?","answers":[{"option":"Popliteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior medial genicular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior tibial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior tibial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Peroneal artery","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles pass through the greater sciatic foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Piriformis","bool":true},{"option":"Quadratus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Superior and inferior gemelli","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What are the contents of the femoral sheath from the lateral to the medial side?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral nerve, femoral artery, and the femoral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein, femoral artery, and the lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein, femoral artery, and the femoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral artery, femoral vein, and the lymphatic vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral nerve, femoral artery, femoral vein, and the inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following structures are present in the femoral canal?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral artery, vein, and the lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic vessels and sometimes deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The femoral sheath is formed by which of the following layers of fascia?","answers":[{"option":"The fascia lata and the membranous layer of the superficial fascia","bool":false},{"option":"The fascia iliaca and fascia transversalis","bool":true},{"option":"The processes vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"The psoas fascia and the fatty layer of the superficial fascia","bool":false},{"option":"the pectineus fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles attach to the lesser tubercle of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Infraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Subscapularis","bool":true},{"option":"Teres minor","bool":false},{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is the longest muscle in the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Iliacus","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas major","bool":false},{"option":"Vastus medialis","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":true},{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscle pairs is involved in the abduction of the upper limb after the first 90 degrees of movement?","answers":[{"option":"Deltoid and levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius and serratus anterior","bool":true},{"option":"Deltoid and supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid and trapezius","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius and levator scapulae","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding the route of the great saphenous vein?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior to the medial malleolus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior to the medial condyle of the tibia and femur","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior to the medial malleolus","bool":true},{"option":"Passes up the lateral side of the leg","bool":false},{"option":"Joins the femoral vein superficial to the fascia lata","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What is the most common site for the fracture of a clavicle?","answers":[{"option":"Junction of lateral three fourth of a clavicle with medial one fourth","bool":false},{"option":"Junction of medial three fourth of a clavicle with lateral one fourth","bool":false},{"option":"Junction of medial two third of a clavicle with lateral one third","bool":true},{"option":"Junction of lateral two third of a clavicle with medial one third","bool":false},{"option":"The mid point of the clavicle","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following types of cells do Howship's lacunae contain?","answers":[{"option":"Chondrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoprogenitor cells","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoclasts","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Cardiac muscle is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Somatic mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Splanchnic mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral plate mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is the reason behind the resilience and shock-absorbing nature of cartilage?","answers":[{"option":"Non-covalent bonding between glycosaminoglycans (GAGs) and proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Regenerative ability of chondrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ossification of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Hydration of glycosaminoglycans (GAGs)","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following fibers is the fastest nerve fiber?","answers":[{"option":"A-gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A-delta fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A-beta fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A-alpha fibers","bool":true},{"option":"A-epsilon fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which orientation is preferred for the X-ray of long bones?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior-anterior (PA) and lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior-posterior (AP) and lateral view","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior-posterior (AP) and oblique view","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior-anterior (PA) and oblique view","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior-posterior (AP) and medial view","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries enter the gluteal region by passing over the piriformis muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral circumflex femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior gluteal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior epigastric artery","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following veins pass through the deltopectoral triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Subclavian vein","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Basilic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary vein","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"To which of the following structures does the flexor retinaculum attach medially?","answers":[{"option":"Tubercle of scaphoid and ridge of trapezium","bool":false},{"option":"Hook of hamate and pisiform","bool":true},{"option":"Pisiform and trapezoid","bool":false},{"option":"Tubercle of scaphoid and hook of hamate","bool":false},{"option":"Ridge of trapezium and hook of hamate","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following veins combine to form the axillary vein?","answers":[{"option":"Basilic vein and brachial vein","bool":true},{"option":"Basilic vein and subclavian vein","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial vein and cephalic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Basilic vein and radial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Basilic vein and cephalic vein","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following pair of joints is involved in the inversion and eversion of the foot?","answers":[{"option":"Talocrural and talocalcanial joint","bool":false},{"option":"Subtalar and talocrural joint","bool":false},{"option":"Subtalar and transverse tarsal joint","bool":true},{"option":"Talotibial and talocalcanial","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse tarsal and tibiotalar joint","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is the keystone of the medial longitudinal arch of the foot?","answers":[{"option":"Navicular bone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcaneal tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Talus head","bool":true},{"option":"Medial cuneiform bone","bool":false},{"option":"Metatarsals","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which muscle divides the axillary artery into three parts?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis minor","bool":true},{"option":"Teres minor","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false},{"option":"Coracobrachialis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"How much additional potential difference is created when the sodium-potassium pump transfers three sodium ions outside the cell and two potassium ions inside the cell?","answers":[{"option":"-2 mV","bool":false},{"option":"-1 mV","bool":false},{"option":"-3 mV","bool":false},{"option":"-4 mV","bool":true},{"option":"-5 mV","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What does a comminuted fracture mean?","answers":[{"option":"A fracture with splintered bones","bool":true},{"option":"A simple fracture","bool":false},{"option":"An open fracture","bool":false},{"option":"A fracture with unaligned bones","bool":false},{"option":"A closed fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Damage to which pair of nerves is responsible for loss of inversion of the foot?","answers":[{"option":"Deep peroneal and tibial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Tibial and common peroneal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial peroneal and sural nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial peroneal and tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial and deep peroneal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which cofactor is necessary for hydroxylation during collagen synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Ascorbate","bool":true},{"option":"Calcitriol","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Folate","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which long bone of the lower limb has the medial malleolus as its normal anatomical part?","answers":[{"option":"Fibula","bool":false},{"option":"Talus","bool":false},{"option":"Navicular bone","bool":false},{"option":"Femur","bool":false},{"option":"Tibia","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which muscle is most likely to be impaired when a person is unable to flex, abduct, and laterally rotate his thigh?","answers":[{"option":"Sartorius","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus medius","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following nerves will be damaged by the fracture of a neck of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following pairs of nerves supply the lumbricals?","answers":[{"option":"Median and radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median and musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial and ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median and ulnar nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Ulnar and musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What is the action of the serratus anterior on the scapula?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Protraction","bool":true},{"option":"Retraction","bool":false},{"option":"Downward rotation","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is responsible for the lateral rotation and flexion of the thigh at the hip joint?","answers":[{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false},{"option":"Vastus lateralis","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is associated with Klumpke's palsy?","answers":[{"option":"Claw hand","bool":true},{"option":"Waitor's tip hand","bool":false},{"option":"Shoulder drop","bool":false},{"option":"Hand of benediction","bool":false},{"option":"Wrist drop","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles attaches to the nuchal ligament?","answers":[{"option":"Rhomboid major","bool":false},{"option":"Rhomboid minor","bool":true},{"option":"Latissimus dorsi","bool":false},{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is not one of the key principles of health education?","answers":[{"option":"Change of behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Creating habits","bool":true},{"option":"Knowing customs","bool":false},{"option":"Learning by doing","bool":false},{"option":"Good relations","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 34-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of inability to extend his leg at the knee joint. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Sciatic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Tibial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Peroneal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"In which of the following conditions does the high turnover osteoporosis occur?","answers":[{"option":"High progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Low calcium and low vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"High estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Low progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Low estrogen","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"If a child's elbow gets fractured and the fractured segment moves posteriorly then which of the following artery will get damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Ulnar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial artery","bool":true},{"option":"Cephalic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Radial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is a cyclooxygenase-1 and cyclooxygenase-2 inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Paracetamol","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Dipyrone","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Antipyrine","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which neurotransmitter is involved in the conduction of superficial pain?","answers":[{"option":"Vasoactive intestinal peptide","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Extraembryonic mesoderm is present in between which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Extraembryonic membrane and cytotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Extraembryonic membrane and syncitiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Exocoelomic membrane and cytotrophoblast","bool":true},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast and cytotrophoblast","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of these is the largest protein in skeletal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Titin","bool":true},{"option":"Actin","bool":false},{"option":"Myosin","bool":false},{"option":"Tropomyosin","bool":false},{"option":"Troponin","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Lumbricals originate from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris","bool":false},{"option":"Palmaris longus","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor digitorum profundus","bool":true},{"option":"Flexor carpi radialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor digitorum superficialis","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The terminal cisternae, lying next to the T-tubules in a sarcomere of skeletal muscle, is a part of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Lysosome","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What is the portion of myofibril between two consecutive Z-lines called?","answers":[{"option":"A band","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcomere","bool":true},{"option":"I band","bool":false},{"option":"H zone","bool":false},{"option":"M line","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The femoral artery is the continuation of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Internal iliac artery at the level of the inguinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac artery above the inguinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":true},{"option":"Internal iliac artery above the inguinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac artery at the level of the inguinal ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The triceps brachii muscle has three heads. Which of the following is the origin of the lateral head of triceps brachii?","answers":[{"option":"Lower half of the anterior surface of humeral shaft","bool":false},{"option":"Upper half of the anterior surface of humeral shaft","bool":false},{"option":"Lower half of the posterior surface of humeral shaft","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Upper half of the posterior surface of humeral shaft","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Myofibrils are formed from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcomeres","bool":false},{"option":"Myosin","bool":false},{"option":"Actin","bool":false},{"option":"Myosin and actin filaments","bool":true},{"option":"Sarcolemma","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 60-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a loss of sensation in the anterolateral aspect of the thigh due to damage to the lateral cutaneous nerve. The lateral cutaneous nerve is a branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sacral plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sciatic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is likely to be paralyzed if the suprascapular notch gets calcified?","answers":[{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false},{"option":"Subscapularis","bool":false},{"option":"Infraspinatus","bool":true},{"option":"Pectolaris major","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct about Paget's disease of bone?","answers":[{"option":"Histologically bone shows a characteristic mosaic pattern","bool":true},{"option":"Children are most commonly affected","bool":false},{"option":"Another name for it is osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"It is due to vitamin D deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"It is more common in Pakistan than in America","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles are innervated by both obturator and sciatic nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Semitendinosus","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor magnus","bool":true},{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which nerve is subject to injury in a fracture of the midshaft of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Musculocutaneous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following structures passes superficial to the flexor retinaculum?","answers":[{"option":"Flexor carpi longus","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor digitorum superficialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi radialis","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar artery","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is/are found in the trochanteric fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator externus, superior gemellus, and inferior gemellus","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus, superior gemellus, and inferior gemellus","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is a powerful adductor and medial rotator of the arm?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis minor","bool":false},{"option":"Teres minor","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false},{"option":"Subscapularis","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles holds fractured clavicle in order to prevent damage to the subclavian vein?","answers":[{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavius","bool":true},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius","bool":false},{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The lateral circumflex femoris artery is a direct branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Profunda femoris artery","bool":true},{"option":"Popliteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct about the inferior gluteal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"It passes anterior to piriformis","bool":false},{"option":"It passes inferior to piriformis","bool":true},{"option":"It pierces through deep fascia","bool":false},{"option":"It gives off cutaneous branches","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A patient is suffering from pain and swelling at the knee joint. He is given aspirin. What is the mechanism of action of aspirin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of platelet formation","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of lipoxygenase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of leukocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of erythrocyte formation","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of cyclooxygenase","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 24-year-old man is brought into the emergency room after he has met a motorbike accident. X-ray shows fracture of shaft of humerus distal to the deltoid tuberosity. Which of the following nerve is likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior interosseous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The parathyroid hormone plays a critical role in calcium homeostasis. Which of the following is seen as the body attempts to maintain the serum calcium levels within the normal range?","answers":[{"option":"Decline in parathyroid hormone levels","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of vitamin D synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Excretion of calcium from kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophy of chondrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Softening of bones","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following ions are required for the exocytosis of neurotransmitters at the neuromuscular junction?","answers":[{"option":"K+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+2 ions","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"In a patient, the iliopsoas is found paralyzed. Which of the following muscle will undergo hypertrophy to compensate for hip flexion?","answers":[{"option":"Vastus intermedius","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Pectineus","bool":false},{"option":"Semimembranosus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor fascia latae","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"In a child suffering from influenza and chickenpox, aspirin is contraindicated because of the risk of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Reye's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Paget's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopetrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is present in the extracellular matrix of cartilage?","answers":[{"option":"Tropomyosin","bool":false},{"option":"Troponin","bool":false},{"option":"Aggrecan","bool":true},{"option":"Titin","bool":false},{"option":"Myosin","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following branch is the major blood supply to the femoral head and neck?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral circumflex femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medial circumflex femoral artery","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following bones is present in the proximal row of carpals?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezium","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezoid","bool":false},{"option":"Hamate","bool":false},{"option":"Capitate","bool":false},{"option":"Lunate","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a component of the adductor canal?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral vein","bool":false},{"option":"Saphenous nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to vastus medialis","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Great saphenous vein","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Fracture of the neck of the femur causes avascular necrosis of the femoral head. Lack of supply from which of the following artery is the reason behind this?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior circumflex femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medial circumflex femoral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct about fibrocartilage?","answers":[{"option":"It is abundant in proteoglycans","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cartilage is of fibrocartilaginous variety","bool":false},{"option":"It is composed of type 2 collagen only","bool":false},{"option":"Regions surrounding lacunae are relatively free of fibers","bool":true},{"option":"It is covered by perichondrium","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The joint between radius and ulna is classified as which type of joint?","answers":[{"option":"Gomphosis","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial","bool":true},{"option":"Suture","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous","bool":false},{"option":"Symphysis","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Flexor carpi ulnaris is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior interosseus branch of median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Dupuytren's contracture is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Median nerve damage","bool":false},{"option":"Thickening of palmar aponeurosis of ulnar side","bool":true},{"option":"Rupture of flexor retinaculum","bool":false},{"option":"Rupture of extensor retinaculum","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve damage","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Scapular anastomosis is formed between which part of the subclavian and axillary artery?","answers":[{"option":"4th part of subclavian and 1st part of axillary","bool":false},{"option":"1st part of subclavian and 3rd part of axillary","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"3rd part of subclavian and 1st part of axillary","bool":false},{"option":"2nd part of subclavian and 3rd part of axillary","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries is not involved in the formation of scapular anastomosis?","answers":[{"option":"Circumflex humeral","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrocervical","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral thoracic","bool":true},{"option":"Suprascapular","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Scapular anastomosis opens up when which of the following arteries is blocked?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal part of radial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal part of axillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Proximal part of subclavian artery","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is present anterior to the adductor canal?","answers":[{"option":"Sartorius","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is present posterior to the adductor canal?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sartorius","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The adductor canal is located in which region of the thigh?","answers":[{"option":"Middle third of thigh","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior thigh","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Upper third of thigh","bool":false},{"option":"Lower third of thigh","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The axillary artery is a continuation of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thoracic artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":true},{"option":"Thyrocervical artery","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following parts of the axillary artery is oriented distal to the pectoralis minor muscle?","answers":[{"option":"3rd part of axillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"1st part of axillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"4th part of axillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"2nd part of axillary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the axillary artery?","answers":[{"option":"Thyrocervical artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior circumflex humeral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Thoraco-acromial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Subscapular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior circumflex humeral artery","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries arises from the third part of the axillary artery?","answers":[{"option":"Subscapular artery","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Radial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"The movement of the little finger is impaired due to the fracture of the elbow. It is due to the rupture of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medial collateral ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Bicipital aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon of flexor carpi ulnaris","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon of flexor carpi radialis","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is correct about the development of skeletal system?","answers":[{"option":"Fingers and toes formation occur due to death of apical ectodermal ridge cells by apoptosis","bool":true},{"option":"Upper limbs develop two days after lower limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Limb development starts in second week of development","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Joints development starts in fourth week of development","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Where does the subclavius insert on the clavicle?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior surface of lateral 2/3rd of clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior surface of lateral 2/3rd of clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of lateral 2/3rd of clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior surface of medial 1/3rd of clavicle","bool":true},{"option":"Sternal head","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Nerve conduction velocity increases with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in diameter of axon","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in thickness of myelin sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Demyelination of axon","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in diameter of axon","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Transverse midshaft fracture of radius and ulna is treated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and plate","bool":true},{"option":"Close reduction and slab","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and nail","bool":false},{"option":"Close reduction and plaster cast","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A boy was unable to raise his arm above the shoulder level due to damage to a nerve. This nerve supplies which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":false},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":true},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Infraspinatus","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which muscle flexes the leg better when the thigh is also flexed?","answers":[{"option":"Short head of biceps femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Semitendinosus","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Long head of biceps femoris","bool":true},{"option":"Semimembranosus","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct about the route of the great saphenous vein?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior to medial malleolus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior to medial epicondyle of femur and tibia","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior to medial epicondyle of femur and tibia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to fascia lata","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"In the 18th to 20th century, the decline in mortality level occurred due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diseases","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Prevention","bool":true},{"option":"Carelessness","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Limping is seen in patients with an impaired function of which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Gluteus medius","bool":true},{"option":"Gluteus maximus","bool":false},{"option":"Semitendinosus","bool":false},{"option":"Semimembranosus","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus abdominis","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Serum levels of which of the following help in the regulation of calcium and phosphorus levels in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"If the potential of a disorder increases, it may result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Disability","bool":true},{"option":"Impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Injury","bool":false},{"option":"Functionality","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Where does cartilage originate from?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Proctoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following terms refers to decreased bone mass?","answers":[{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Paget's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopenia","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which one of the following can the venom of the sea snake be categorized as?","answers":[{"option":"Neurotoxic","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculotoxic","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatotoxic","bool":false},{"option":"Myotoxic","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrotoxic","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Tendon of which of the following muscles passes through lesser sciatic foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false},{"option":"Quadratus femoris","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus medius","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"An avalanche is an event that occurs when a cohesive slab of snow lying upon a weaker layer of snow fractures and slides down a steep slope. Which type of disaster is 'avalanche'?","answers":[{"option":"Acts of terrorism","bool":false},{"option":"Meteorological","bool":false},{"option":"Tectonic","bool":false},{"option":"Structure failures","bool":false},{"option":"Topographical","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A patient has suffered a fracture of the surgical neck of the humerus. Which nerve is most closely related to this structure?","answers":[{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Circumflex scapular vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Profunda brachii","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 55-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with the history of falling on his outstretched hand with flexed elbow. The medial epicondyle is avulsed. Which of the following muscle does not take origin from the fractured region?","answers":[{"option":"Flexor carpi radialis","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor digitorum profundus","bool":true},{"option":"Palmaris longus","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor digitorum superficialis","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 43-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of pain in his tibia bone for the past two years. Upon investigation, he opens up about his history of extra-marital affairs. A Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) report reveals the development of gumma as well. Which microorganism could he be suspected to be infected by?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 20-year-old man falls from the parallel bar during the Olympic trial. A neurologic examination reveals that he has a lesion of the lateral cord of the brachial plexus. Which of the following muscles is most likely to be weakened by this injury?","answers":[{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":true},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false},{"option":"Latissimus dorsi","bool":false},{"option":"Subscapularis","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A young woman is unable to climb up the stairs. Which of the following muscles is most likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus minimus","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteus maximus","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is the principal protein present in bones?","answers":[{"option":"Collagen type I","bool":true},{"option":"Collagen type IV","bool":false},{"option":"Fibronectin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen type III","bool":false},{"option":"Elastin","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following organisms can get a person osteomyelitis if they already have genitourinary tract infection?","answers":[{"option":"E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococci","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococci","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A person is trying to extend his thumb but finds himself unable to do so. Which of the following nerves must be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Axillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve passing between superficial and deep muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve passing superficial to extensor retinaculum","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles originate from 3rd to 5th ribs?","answers":[{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Teres minor","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis minor","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding generation of an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"The polarity of a cell increases","bool":false},{"option":"Negative ions move from extracellular to intracellular compartment","bool":false},{"option":"Positive ions move from the extracellular to intracellular compartment","bool":true},{"option":"Inside of the cell is more negative than the outside","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium channels open throughout the membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a part of the roof of a cubital fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Bicipital aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"On the gluteal surface of the ilium, where is the origin of the gluteus medius muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior gluteal line","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior gluteal line","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior gluteal line","bool":false},{"option":"Between posterior and superior gluteal line","bool":false},{"option":"Between anterior and posterior gluteal line","bool":true}]},{"id":114,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"When the membrane is only permeable to K+ ions, the ratio of K+ inside to outside the cell is 35:1. What is the Nernst potential across the cell membrane in this case?","answers":[{"option":"-85 mV","bool":false},{"option":"-70 mV","bool":false},{"option":"-94 mV","bool":true},{"option":"-90 mV","bool":false},{"option":"-61 mV","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 36-year-old woman with a lump in the breast was diagnosed with breast cancer and underwent a mastectomy and surgical removal of axillary lymph nodes. After the surgery, she was unable to use one of her upper limbs, of the same side of the surgery, to climb. Which of the following nerves was damaged?","answers":[{"option":"DorsaI scapular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Subscapular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracodorsal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Long thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"SuprascapuIar nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is not supplied by the obturator nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Hamstring part of adductor magnus","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor brevis","bool":false},{"option":"GraciIis","bool":false},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following passes through the adductor canal?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve to the vastus lateralis","bool":false},{"option":"Great saphenous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Small saphenous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein","bool":true}]},{"id":118,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of acetaminophen?","answers":[{"option":"InhIblts COX-1","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits COX-2","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits COX-1 and COX-3","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits COX-1, COX-2, and COX-3","bool":true},{"option":"InhIblts COX-3","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of methylxanthine?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha-adrenergic receptor stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of intracellular sodium levels","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-adrenergic receptor stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of intracellular fluoride levels","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of phosphodiesterase","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 5-year-old presents with symptoms of viral infection. Due to the risk of which of the following would aspirin not be prescribed to him?","answers":[{"option":"Chediak-Higashi syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Thorn's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Bantis syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Barlow syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Reye's syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":121,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the joints in the hand?","answers":[{"option":"The interphalangeal joints are hinge joints","bool":false},{"option":"There is restricted movement at the intercarpal joints","bool":false},{"option":"The metacarpophalangeal joints are synovial condyloid joints","bool":false},{"option":"At the metacarpophalangeal joint, the base of the phalanx articulates with the the head of the metacarpal","bool":false},{"option":"No movement occurs at metacarpocarpal joint of the thumb","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following modalities should be used for upper limb soft tissues?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Computerized tomography (CT)","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":true},{"option":"Fluoroscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear imaging","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is one of the key principles of health education?","answers":[{"option":"Awareness","bool":false},{"option":"Promotion","bool":false},{"option":"Trial","bool":false},{"option":"Motivation","bool":true},{"option":"Advocacy","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"At the knee joint, the patellar ligament and oblique popliteal ligament respectively correspond to which of the following pairs?","answers":[{"option":"GraciIis and biceps","bool":false},{"option":"Quadriceps and semitendinosus","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps and semitendinosus","bool":false},{"option":"Quadriceps and gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Quadriceps and semimembranosus","bool":true}]},{"id":125,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following structures is intracapsular at the knee joint?","answers":[{"option":"Patellar ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteus tendon","bool":true},{"option":"Tibial collateral ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Biceps femoris tendon","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique patellar ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the developmental disorders of the skeletal system?","answers":[{"option":"Osteopetrosis is characteristized by lesser bone mass","bool":false},{"option":"Thanatophoric dysplasia is harmless","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis is marked by denser bone","bool":false},{"option":"Achondroplasia is the most common cause of dwarfism","bool":true},{"option":"Osteopetrosis is brittle bone disease","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 15-year-old boy is rushed to the emergency room after an automobile accident. He has weak knee extension, loss of function of quadriceps compartment, and loss of sensation over the anteromedial thigh and medial side of the calf. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior gluteal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Sciatic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior gluteal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 12-year-old boy suffers an accident that injures the posterior triangle of his neck. He is unable to raise his hand to comb his hair. Which of the following muscles is most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Latissimus dorsi","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":true},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which part of the iliac crest is the attachment for the gluteus maximus muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral slope","bool":true},{"option":"Intermediate area","bool":false},{"option":"Internal lip","bool":false},{"option":"Medial slope","bool":false},{"option":"External lip","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A 14-year-old boy was brought to the emergency room after he had slipped from a bike. He was observed to have restricted movement at his left knee while resistance in extension in right knee was also noticed. Which muscle might be involved in this?","answers":[{"option":"Flexors","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteus","bool":false},{"option":"Soleus","bool":false},{"option":"Hamstrings","bool":false},{"option":"Quadriceps","bool":true}]},{"id":131,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"A patient was given an intramuscular injection. In which muscle is it commonly administered?","answers":[{"option":"Psoas minor","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas major","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":true},{"option":"Extrinsic muscles","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"If the loss of motor function is observed in the anterior thigh and sensory function of the medial and anterior leg. Which of the following nerves is most likely suspected to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Radial","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral","bool":true},{"option":"Sciatic","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which one of the following is not a principle of health education?","answers":[{"option":"Knowing the customs","bool":false},{"option":"Trial","bool":true},{"option":"Good human relations","bool":false},{"option":"Learning by doing","bool":false},{"option":"Motivation","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"An X-ray shows an injury to the axillary nerve. Which muscle is most likely to be affected by this?","answers":[{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major","bool":false},{"option":"Infraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":true},{"option":"Teres major","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is not attached to either the lesser or greater tubercle of humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Subscapularis","bool":false},{"option":"Teres minor","bool":false},{"option":"Infraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Deltoid","bool":true},{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"As a result of road traffic accident, a person lost his supination. Which nerve is most likely to be damaged here?","answers":[{"option":"Musculocutaneous","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial","bool":false},{"option":"Radial","bool":true},{"option":"Ulnar","bool":false},{"option":"Median","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"If all the vessels of the cruciate anastomosis are cut off, which artery will supply the femur?","answers":[{"option":"Superior gluteal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medial circumflex femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral circumflex femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"First perforating artery","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is an active form of vitamin D?","answers":[{"option":"1,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol","bool":true},{"option":"25-hydroxycholecalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"Niacin","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Where is the triad present in skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"I band","bool":false},{"option":"A-I junction","bool":true},{"option":"M band","bool":false},{"option":"A band","bool":false},{"option":"Z line","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which function is impaired by the fracture in the midshaft of ulna and radius?","answers":[{"option":"Wrist extension","bool":true},{"option":"Elbow flexion","bool":false},{"option":"Wrist flexion","bool":false},{"option":"Supination and pronation","bool":false},{"option":"Elbow extension","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is true about 'myosin filament'?","answers":[{"option":"It is present in A band","bool":true},{"option":"It contains titin","bool":false},{"option":"Isotropic to light","bool":false},{"option":"It is a structural protein","bool":false},{"option":"It is present in I band","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"Which of the following is the safest and easiest way of treating midshaft fracture of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Locking plate fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Pain relief medication only","bool":false},{"option":"Splint","bool":true},{"option":"Intramedullary nail","bool":false},{"option":"External fixation","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"1st-year/locomotor/2019","question":"'Geriatrics' is a branch of medicine that deals with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cure and rehabilitation of the elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Prevention and rehabilitation of the elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Diagnosis of illness of the elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Management of the illness of the elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Prevention, cure and rehabilitation from the disease in the older adults","bool":true}]}]
export default arr